A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, F-L FA392
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Fahs, Charles B.
  - Trip to the Far East, 1955 April 15-June 15; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 143 pages (Box 142, Reel M Fah 4, Frame 1,016)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs takes a trip to East Asia to survey Asian and American study programs at various universities.
    Humanities; Philippines; Indonesia; Philosophy and religion; Education; Japan; Diaries; History; Linguistics; Art; United States
  - 1955 June 17-30, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); 15 pages (Box 142, Reel M Fah 4, Frame 1,000)
    Fahs talks with professionals in the field of Humanities concerning American studies, developing a library collection and regarding a project on suburban population of New York City as a market for performing arts.
    Education; Art; Humanities; Linguistics; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; History; Diaries; Philosophy and religion; United States
  - 1955 July 1-October 28, Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 133 pages (Box 142, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 1)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. A focus of this diary contains discussions on performing arts and East Asian studies.
    Linguistics; Music; Diaries; Performing arts; Philosophy and religion; Education; History; Humanities; Libraries; Art; Dance; United States; Theater
  - 1955 November 1-December 30, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); 100 pages (Box 142, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 134)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs attends the Meeting of the Japan Society, Conference on Slavic and East European Studies and Latin American Discussions. He also visits the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts. A RF grant brings drama within the scope of their activities.
    History; Humanities; Linguistics; Diaries; Philosophy and religion; United States; Art; Education; East Asia; Drama
  - 1956 January 4-13, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); 19 pages (Reel M Fah 5, Frame 234, Box 142)
    The bulk of this brief dairy contains discussions between Fahs and the American Shakespeare Festival Theatre and Academy.
    Humanities; Theater; United States; Diaries
  - Trip to Mexico - Index, 1956 January 14-24; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton) (Box 142, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 253)
    Sope and Contents note
    indexes (reference sources); Mexico
  - Trip to Mexico, 1956 January 14-24; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 33 pages (Box 142, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 258)
    Fahs travels to Mexico talks to talk to professionals in the field of Humanities. He surveys and tours the Mexican Writing Center, Colegio de Mexico and University of Mexico.
    Mexico; Libraries; Diaries; Creative writing; Education; History; Humanities
  - 1956 January 25-February 10, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - Trip to Colombia - Index, 1956 February 12-21; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton) (Box 142, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 329)
    Index; Trip to Columbia; 3 pages.
    Education; Colombia; indexes (reference sources); Humanities
  - Trip to Colombia, 1956 February 12-21; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 22 pages (Box 142, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 332)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs takes a trip to Columbia and surveys Universidad de los Andes and Universidad de Antioquia
    Diaries; Colombia; Bibliography; Education; Libraries; Humanities; Linguistics
  - 1956 February 23-March 1, Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 20 pages (Box 142, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 354)
    Diaries; Humanities; United States; Art; Education
  - Trip to Pittsburgh, 1956 March 2-3; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 8 pages (Reel M Fah 5, Frame 374, Box 142)
    Fahs takes a trip to Pittsburgh, PA and surveys educational television programs for children and views art prints.
    Educational television programs; Humanities; Education; Educational broadcasting; Art; Diaries; United States
  - 1956 March 5-April 8, Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 76 pages (Box 142, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 382)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs attends the Meeting on "History of the Americas Project" and Far Eastern Association meeting. He prepares for his trip to East Asia and discusses print art.
    United States; Theater; Humanities; Diaries; Linguistics; Education; History; East Asia; Art
  - Trip to the Far East - Index, 1956 April 8-June 8; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities. (Reel M Fah 5, Frame 458, Box 143)
  - Trip to the Far East, 1956 April 8-June 8; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); 179 pages (Reel M Fah 5, Frame 468, Box 143)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs travels to East Asia. Primary topics on this diary include Japanese religion, the Seminar on modern China, and performing and creative arts.
    Philippines; Philosophy and religion; History; Humanities; Indonesia; Japan; Korea; Libraries; Linguistics; Music; Theater; Education; Art; Religion; Diaries
  - 1956 June 9-October 16, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); 184 pages (Reel M Fah 5, Frame 647, Box 143)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs attends Seminar to Develop a Project in the field of "Asian-Western Cultural Relations" and American Press Institute Seminar for Latin American Journalists.
    Education; Diaries; Humanities; Philosophy and religion; Religion; Theater; United States
  - 1956 October 17-December 13, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); 72 pages (Box 143, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 832)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs tours Stanford University and UCLA.
    Music; Libraries; Religion; Art; Diaries; Education; Humanities
  - Trip to Mexico - Index, 1956 December 8-18; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities. (Box 143, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 904)
    Index; Trip to Mexico; 2 pages.
    indexes (reference sources); Humanities; Mexico; Education
  - Trip to Mexico, 1956 December 8-18; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 21 pages (Box 143, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 906)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs takes a trip to Mexico and gets updated on the contemporary Mexican history project, the Mexican Writing Center and Colegio de Mexico.
    Diaries; Creative writing; Libraries; Humanities; Theater; Mexico; Translations; Dance; History; Education
  - 1956 December 19-1957 April 5, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); 189 pages (Box 143, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 927)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs tours Howard University and surveys their African studies program, and visits UCLA to review their English language education program.
    United States; Theater; Religion; Philosophy and religion; East Asia; Africa; Linguistics; Humanities; Diaries; History; Education
  - Trip to the Far East - Index, 1957 April 15-June 28; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton) (Reel M Fah 6, Frame 1, Box 143)
  - Trip to the Far East, 1957 April 15-June 28; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 201 pages (Box 143, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 12)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs tours the Far East to focus on RF projects in intercultural studies and the arts.
    Bali; Art; City planning; Linguistics; Diaries; Music; Architecture; Libraries; Indonesia; Humanities; Lebanon; Japan; Education; Drama; History; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; Religion; Philosophy and religion; Taiwan; Singapore; Thailand
  - 1957 July 1-October 11, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); 128 pages (Reel M Fah 6, Frame 213, Box 144)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs travels to North Carolina and New England to survey dramatic and performing arts. He attends the U.S. National Commission for UNESCO meeting of Advisory Group on project on Mutual Appreciation of East-West Cultural Values.
    Education; Drama; Diaries; Humanities; History; United States; Performing arts; Art; Dance
  - Trip to Europe, 1957 October 12-19; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); 21 pages (Reel M Fah 6, Frame 341, Box 144)
    In this brief diary Fahs takes a trip to Europe and tours University of Fribourg, Free University and International Institute for Social History. The emphasis of RF interest in these institutions focuses on ethics and one political and social philosophy.
    Switzerland; Education; Germany; Humanities; Libraries; Netherlands; Philosophy and religion; Diaries; Political science; Slavic studies; Social sciences
  - 1957 October 22-November 7, Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 27 pages (Box 144, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 362)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs travels to North Carolina and New England to survey dramatic and performing arts.
    Diaries; Education; Humanities; United States
  - Trip to the West Coast, 1957 November 7-15; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); 23 pages (Box 144, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 389)
    Fahs travels to the West Coast to survey RF interest programs such as English language education, Stanford University Seminar for Business Administrators of Japanese Universities and to attend a UNESCO conference.
    Diaries; Art; East Asia; United States; Religion; Music; Humanities; Ethics; Education
  - 1957 November 18-December 31, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); 73 pages (Reel M Fah 6, Frame 412, Box 144)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs attends Program of Advanced Religious Studies at Union Theological Seminary, meeting in Washington of the Ad Hoc Advisory Committee on the Third Major Project. He travels to Gambier, Ohio.
    Translations; Theater; Religion; Prints; Performing arts; Humanities; Education; Dance; Art; Diaries; United States
  - 1958 January 2-April 1, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); 167 pages (Box 144, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 485)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs takes trips to the Southwest, Washington D.C. and Cornell University.
    Diaries; Native Americans; United States; Humanities; Music; East Asia; Education; Dance; Anthropology
  - Trip to Korea - Index, 1958 April 4-May 5; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities. (Box 144, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 653)
    Index; Trip to Japan and Korea; 8 pages.
    Korea; indexes (reference sources); Japan; Education; Humanities
  - Trip to Korea, 1958 April 4-May 5; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 86 pages (Box 144, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 661)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs tours Korean and Japanese Universities to survey RF intercultural humanities projects that focus on history, philosophy and American studies. During his time in Korea the Korean dictionary and Encyclopedia of Science are discussed.
    Diaries; Art; Music; Libraries; Religion; Humanities; History; Korea; Japan; City planning; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; Education
  - 1958 May 6-August 22, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); 117 pages (Reel M Fah 6, Frame 744, Box 144)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs discusses Asian, Arabic and Russian studies.
    Humanities; Education; Libraries; Language and languages; Theater; Diaries; United States
  - Trip to Southeast Asia - Index, 1958 August 24-September 29; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities. (Reel M Fah 6, Frame 864, Box 144)
    Index; Trip to Southeast Asia; 5 pages.
    indexes (reference sources); Southeast Asia; Education; Humanities
  - Trip to Southeast Asia, 1958 August 24-September 29; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 64 pages (Box 144, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 869)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs takes a trip to the Southeast to survey RF funded intercultural projects such as language studies. Music and theater are also discussed in the diary.
    Philippines; Theater; Humanities; Indonesia; Language and languages; Music; Diaries; Education
  - 1958 September 26-December 31, Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 152 pages (Box 144, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 933)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs takes a trip to Hebrew Union College and University of California at Berkeley.
    Music; Prints; Art; Religion; United States; Education; Humanities; Language and languages; Diaries; Linguistics
  - 1959 January 2-April 2, Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 148 pages (Box 145, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 1,085)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs visits Harvard, McGill, Yale, Drew, and Westminster Choir College.
    Diaries; United States; Music; Economics; Education; Humanities; Libraries; Anthropology; Archaeology; Dance
  - 1959 April 4-October 9 (Box 145, Reel M Fah 7, Frame 1)
  - Trip to Canada, Japan, and Okinawa - Index, 1959 April 4-May 2; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton) (Reel M Fah 7, Frame 5, Box 145)
    Index; Trip to Canada, Japan and Okinawa; 6 pages.